Abdul Ahad Mughal

Mobile: +923407988223

E-mail: mr.abdulahad1994@gmail.com

579 street #54 I-10/1 Islamabad, Pakistan

Profile:

Over 4 years of experience solution-oriented professional focusing on area like J2EE Development and leadership with vast knowledge of Software Analysis and Design in the domain of Revenue, Tax Management systems, Web Application and Product life cycle Management System.

Also work on Optimization, Application Optimization/Performance Tuning, process engineering, modelling and development of core J2EE implementations as well as Support.

Skills Summary:

- ➤ Java / J2EE
- Spring Boot
- Spring Core / Spring MVC / Spring Data JPA / Hibernate
- Spring Transaction Management / GitHub / TFS
- ➤ Jasper Reports / IReport
- PrimeFaces / JSF / JSP
- Oracle / MySQL / SQL Server
- > PHP / Laravel
- WordPress / Magento / Shopify / Webflow
- > HTML / CSS / Bootstrap
- React JS
- Vue JS
- > Python
- SEO / On-Page SEO / Page Speed Optimization
- > Tools: IntelliJ Idea / Eclipse / Visual Studio / Atom / PHP Storm / PyCharm / Toad

Employment History:

> Pakistan Revenue Automation Limited (Owned By FBR)

April 2020 – to date

Software Engineer

Craft Communications Lahore, Pakistan Full Stack Web Developer September 2019 – March 2020

Tech Garage Lahore, Pakistan Web Developer September 2018– August 2019

Education:

- > 2014-2018 (BSSE) COMSATS University Islamabad Campus Abbottabad, Pakistan
- > Intermediate NACSIT Bahawalpur, Pakistan
- > Matriculation, Al-Farooq Public School & Colleges System Bahawalpur, Pakistan

Projects:

IRIS Tax Payer (FBR)	Current J2EE
Automatic Exchange of Information System AEOIS (FBR)	Current J2EE
Tax Asaan Portal (FBR)	Current J2EE
Punjab Revenue Authority PRA (FBR)	J2EE
Data Finder	J2EE
Hospital Management System	Java
Modern Testing Service	Laravel
E-commerce Stores	Magento
Woo-commerce	WordPress
Pak Tour Guide	PHP
Pakbiz Database	PHP
KAcards	Laravel
Myhatravels	PHP
Dharty.pk	Laravel
Quote4life.ca	Laravel

Responsibilities in PRAL (FBR):

- > Update and maintain the current IRIS, AEOIS, Tax Asaan portal
- Adding new features in IRIS, AEOIS, Tax Asaan portal
- Creating and testing workflows as per CRF requirement
- Front development and Backend development of new modules in portal
- Resolving the issues assigned by after QA
- Creating and maintaining reports of IRIS, AEOIS, Tax Asaan portal
- Bulk data export to excel handling
- > Portal Frontend responsiveness
- Custom tags creation
- ➤ Integration of REST / SOAP API's with applications
- > Database operations and maintenance
- Query Optimization
- Creating dynamic frontend components
- Web Service Client implementation
- Technology Stack: Java 7 and / J2EE / Spring / Oracle / Hibernate / PrimeFaces / JSF

Responsibilities Craft Communications:

- Developing new website and web portals from scratch
- Managing and updating existing websites
- Custom theme development
- Custom CRM development
- ➢ SEO
- Deployment on live servers
- Restful API's development in Laravel
- Project management
- ➤ E-commerce and Woo-commerce stores development
- Database creation, normalization, maintenance

Responsibilities in Tech Garage:

- WordPress websites from scratch or theme based development
- Custom WordPress theme development
- Developing Magento stores
- Managing multiple stores